Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES III. Publications, 1930-80
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PUBLICATIONS
  - "Population Crisis via [sic, should be "vs."] Peace and Prosperity," Nobel Laureate's Declaration 1962 (Box 97, Folder 97)
  - "PPWP Presents A New Multi Purpose Exhibit," 1965 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - "Population Crisis," By Roy O. Greep, Harvard Alumni Bulletin 1967 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - "Population Crisis," By William Draper, Jr., PPFA, Annual Mtg. Lasker Awards Dinner Talk 1960 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - "Population Crisis, The: Twentieth Century Challenge," Annual Meeting 1966 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - "Population Crisis, The," Donald B. Strauss, Statement to Com. on Resolutions and Platforms, Democratic Convention 1964 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - [The] Population Dilemma, Edited by Philip M. Hauser (American Assembly) 1963 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Population Expansion, H.S. Study, Reprint, American Biology Teacher 1964 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - "Population Growth and the Individual," By David E. Lilienthal, Annual Mtg. Speech 1965 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - "Population Growth and the Future of Black Folk," By Eleanor Holmes Norton, Reprint 1973 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - "The Population Issue, Time for Action," 1964-1965 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Population Pressure, Resource Unit, Baltimore City Public Schools 1967 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Population, The Problem of Practical Catholic Applications, University of Notre Dame Press 1964 (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Problem of Population, Moral and Theological Considerations, Donald N. Barrett, Editor 1964 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - "[The] Population Problem," By Dorothy L. Nortman, The Population Council 1965 (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - Poblacion, Panel Discussion, Spanish, Wash. D.C., Org. of American States, Speeches 1964 (Box 98, Folder 15)
  - Population, Panel Discussion, Wash. D.C., Org. of Amer. States, Speeches 1964 (Box 98, Folder 16)
  - Population Editorials, Guy Irving Burch 1939 (Box 98, Folder 17)
  - "Population Explosion," Bishops' Proposal, Reprint, Science 1962 (Box 98, Folder 18)
  - "Population Explosion," by Karl Sax 1956 (Box 98, Folder 19)
  - "Population Explosion Demands World-Wide Action," Rev. John A. O'Brien 1964 (Box 98, Folder 20)
  - "Population and Human Destiny," Julian Huxley, Reprint, Harper's Magazine 1950 (Box 98, Folder 21)
  - "Population and Peace," Guy Irving Burch, undated (Box 98, Folder 22)
  - "Population and Peace," Dr. Henry Pratt Fairchild 1944 (Box 98, Folder 23)
  - "Population Policy for the U.S.," P.K. Whelpton 1939 (Box 98, Folder 24)
  - Population Problems, Administration Ready to Help on Above 1961 (Box 98, Folder 25)
  - "Pop. Problem of Foreign Aid," Reprint, N.Y. Times, By J. Reston 1963 (Box 98, Folder 26)
  - "Population Pressure Breeds War," 1954? (Box 98, Folder 27)
  - "Population, Poverty and Peace," By John Nuveen 1964 (Box 98, Folder 28)
  - Population Research and Study Centers, Prepared by PPWP Library 1967 (Box 98, Folder 29)
  - "Population Threatens Prosperity," Joseph J. Spengler 1956 (Box 98, Folder 30)
  - Population: "World Population Problems," By Philip M. Hauser, Headline Series, No. 174 1965 (Box 98, Folder 31)
  - "Population Trends and Public Health Problems," 1940 (Box 98, Folder 32)
  - "Population, The United Nations and The United States," 1961 (Box 98, Folder 33)
  - "Population and the War," By B. Liber, M.D. 1944 (Box 98, Folder 34)
  - "World's Population Rises of [sic, should be "at"] Peak Rate," Reprint, New York Times, By Lawrence O'Kane 1964 (Box 98, Folder 35)
  - "The Positive Policy Handbook (Organization Statements Supporting Sexual Health and Education Services for Youths)," Youth and Student Affairs 1975 (Box 98, Folder 36)
  - [The] World's Exploding Population, Eliz McMasters 1960 (Box 98, Folder 37)
  - Posters, undated (Box 98, Folder 38)
  - "Post-Partum Sterilization," Reprint, Amer. Journal of Obs. and Gyn., Hewitt, H.P., M.D. 1940 (Box 98, Folder 39)
  - The Poverty of Abundance, American Business and the World Population Crisis 1966 (Box 98, Folder 40)
  - "Poverty and Birth Control," Reprint, N.Y. Times 1964 (Box 98, Folder 41)
  - "Poverty and Family Planning," New York Times 1964 (Box 98, Folder 42)
  - "Poverty, Family Planning and [The] Great Society," By Michael Harrington, Annual Mtg. Speech, Oct. 1965 (Box 98, Folder 43)
  - "Poverty and Public Health," Murray Grant, M.D., D.P.H., Reprint from Public Welfare, 4/65 1965 (Box 98, Folder 44)
  - Practice of Contraception, undated (Box 98, Folder 45)
  - Practicing Physician, Community and Question of Moralities, M.S. Calderone 1965 (Box 98, Folder 46)
  - "A Practitioner's Handbook for Local Community Leaders," By Wm. W. Biddle, Ph.D. 1953 (Box 98, Folder 47)
  - "Pregnancy Fear Major Factor in Marital Discord," By Dr. Robert Laidlaw 1960 (Box 98, Folder 48)
  - "Pregnancy Spacing in the South Carolina Public Health Program," 1940 (Box 98, Folder 49)
  - "Pregnancy, Teenagers and the Law, 1974," By Eve W. Paul, Harriet F. Pilpel and Nancy Wechsler, Perspectives, Vol. 6, No. 3, Summer 1974 (Box 98, Folder 50)
  - "Pregnancy Spacing in the Rural Public Health," By Robt. E. Seibels, M.D. 1942 (Box 98, Folder 51)
  - "Preconceptual Care," Reprint, Southern Medical Journal, By H.P. Hewitt, M.D. 1939 (Box 98, Folder 52)
  - "Prelate's Accusation," Editorial from N.Y. Times, Reprinted 1966 (Box 98, Folder 53)
  - "Premarital Consultation," R.L. Dickinson, M.D. 1941 (Box 98, Folder 54)
  - "Premarital Counseling," By Eleanor Hamilton, Spring 1959 (Box 98, Folder 55)
  - "Premarital Counseling," By Granger Westberg 1958 (Box 98, Folder 56)
  - "Premarital Examination," By Grace Naismith, Today's Health, April 1964 (Box 98, Folder 57)
  - "Premarital Medical Examination," 1954 (Box 98, Folder 58)
  - "Preparing for Parenthood," Frederick Osborn, American Eugenics Society 1951 (Box 98, Folder 59)
  - "Present Dilemma and the Way Out," 1935 (Box 98, Folder 60)
  - "President Johnson on Population and Family Planning," Internat'l Education, Before Congress 1966 (Box 98, Folder 61)
  - President Johnson's Statement Concerning Population, Before Congress, January 4, 1965 (Box 98, Folder 62)
  - Presidential Address Given by Theodore R. Robie, Dec. 1947 (Box 98, Folder 63)
  - "The Prevention of Conception," By Abraham Stone, 1955, Revised by Dr. Calderone 1955, 1961 (Box 98, Folder 64)
  - Press Stories 1935 (Box 98, Folder 65)
  - "Preventive Medicine and Epidemiology," Dr. J.E. Gordon and Dr. T.H. Ingalls, 3/54, Reprint, Amer. Jnl. of Med. Sciences, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 66)
  - "Preventive Psychiatry and Family Planning," Reprint, Journal of Marriage and Family 1964 (Box 98, Folder 67)
  - "Preview of the Post War Generation," Reprint from Fortune, March 1943 (Box 98, Folder 68)
  - "Problem of Diagnosis of Marital Discord," By Regina Flesch 1949 (Box 98, Folder 69)
  - "[The] Problem of Infertility," By Grace Naismith, Reprint, Reader's Digest 1954 (Box 98, Folder 70)
  - "Problems of Growing Up," By Eva M. Dodge, June 1944 (Box 98, Folder 71)
  - "Production of a Vaginal Epitthelium," By John R. Baker, Reprint, Journal of Contraception, 1938 (Box 98, Folder 72)
  - "[A] Program for Family Health," By Dr. Nadina Kavinoky 1934 (Box 98, Folder 73)
  - Progress Reports: B.C. Clinical Research Bureau 1934-35, 1937 (Box 98, Folder 74)
  - "Pros and Cons of the Pill," reprint, Time magazine 1969 (Box 98, Folder 75)
  - "[The] Prospects of Birth Control in Puerto Rico," 1953 (Box 98, Folder 76)
  - "Protestant Birth Control Views," Prepared by Right Rev. James A. Pike 1958 (Box 98, Folder 77)
  - "A Protestant View of Population Control," By Richard M. Fagley 1960 (Box 98, Folder 78)
  - "Psychiatric Aspects of Contraception," By Dr. Carl Menninger 1943 (Box 98, Folder 79)
  - Psychology of Parenthood and Religion's Responsibility, By Dr. O. Spurgeon English, undated (Box 98, Folder 80)
  - "Public Health Contraception Service," undated (Box 98, Folder 81)
  - "[The] Public Health Approach to Contraception," 1937 (Box 98, Folder 82)
  - "Public Health Aspects of Family Planning," By Mary S. Calderone 1964 (Box 98, Folder 83)
  - "[The] Public Health Nurse and Planned Parenthood," 1943? (Box 98, Folder 84)
  - "Public Information," Annual Meeting 1942 (Box 98, Folder 85)
  - "Purpose: Survival," Basil Rathbone Featured 1957? (Box 98, Folder 86)
  - "Public Policy in Regard to Birth Control Services," By Alonzo S. Yerby, M.D., Rep., N. England Jnl. of MD 1966 (Box 98, Folder 87)
  - "Quality of Life," 1939? (Box 98, Folder 88)
  - "Quality of Life," 1955 (Box 98, Folder 89)
  - "Quest for Fertility Control: A Program of Research," 1955 (Box 98, Folder 90)
  - "Questions and Answers About the Birth Control 'Pill'," 1962, 1964-65 (Box 98, Folder 91)
  - "Questions and Answers About Intrauterine Contraceptive Devices," 1965, 1974 (Box 98, Folder 92)
  - "Race Building in a Democracy," By Henry Pratt Fairchild 1940 (Box 98, Folder 93)
  - "Racket in Contraceptives," American Mercury, Reprint 1950 (Box 98, Folder 94)
  - Radio, undated (Box 98, Folder 95)
  - "Ready Made Birth Control Program," 1936 (Box 98, Folder 96)
  - "[The] Realm of the Red Queen,"1956 (Box 98, Folder 97)
  - "Record of Growth, Service and Need," Cleveland's 35th Street Clinic 1955 (Box 98, Folder 98)
  - "Recruiting Low-Income Families for Family Life Education Programs," Child Study Association Publications 1965 (Box 98, Folder 99)
  - Reverence for Life Kit 1963 (Box 98, Folder 100)
  - "Referred to Planned Parenthood," undated (Box 98, Folder 101)
  - "Religion and Birth Control," Edited by Jihn Clover Monsma 1965 (Box 98, Folder 102)
  - "Religion's Responsibility in Marriage and Parenthood," 25th Anniversary Dinner, Out of Print 1946 (Box 98, Folder 103)
  - "Religion Looks at Planned Parenthood," Family Week Pamphlet 1951 (Box 98, Folder 104)
  - Report of Your Contribution to Planned Parenthood, Campaign 1952 (Box 98, Folder 105)
  - "Report of Planned Parenthood Services in New York City," 1946? (Box 98, Folder 106)
  - Report Forms, undated (Box 98, Folder 107)
  - "Report of Sub-Committee on Birth Control of the National Medical Assn.," 1943 (Box 98, Folder 108)
  - "Report of Committee to Study Contraceptive Practices and Related Problems," Reprint, Journal A.M.A. 1936 (Box 98, Folder 109)
  - "Report on Family Planning," U.S. Govt., Dept. Health, Ed. and Welfare, Sept. 1966 (Box 98, Folder 110)
  - "A Report on Contraceptive Material," Feb. 1950 (Box 98, Folder 111)
  - "A Report on Contraceptive Material," Consumers Union 1939 (Box 98, Folder 112)
  - "Report on Fertility Points Up, Population Dilemma," Reprint, Evening Star 1962 (Box 98, Folder 113)
  - "Research in Human Reproduction," undated (Box 98, Folder 114)
  - Resolution, undated (Box 98, Folder 115)
  - Resolution, General Federation of Women's Clubs, Statement on Family Planning 1966 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Resolution, Nat'l Association of Social Workers 1962 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Resolution on Family Planning, Nat'l Urban League 1964 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Resolution on Planned Parenthood by American Religious Leaders 1943-44, 1947 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - "Responsible Parenthood," Statements Adopted by Nat'l Council of Churches of Christ 1961 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - "Responsibility for the Health of Tomorrows Family," 24th Annual Meeting Dinner Proceedings 1945 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - "Review of Recent Progress," 1942 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - "The Rising Furor Over Sex Education," Luther G. Baker, Jr. 1969 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - "Road to Survival on this Plundered Planet," 1949 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Dr. John Rock, "It is Time to End the Birth Control Fight," 1963, Sat. Eve. Post, Reprint, 1963 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - "The Role of Family Planning in the Reduction of Poverty," Arthur Campbell, Reprint 1968 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - "[The] Role of the Gynecologist in Family Planning and Marriage Counseling," By J. Allen Offen, M.D. 1959 (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - "[The] Role of Hospital Nurses in Family Planning," By Gitta Meier, Reprint, American Journal of Nursing 1965 (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - "[The] Role of Planned Parenthood," Dr. A.F. Guttmacher, Reprint 1965 (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - "[The] Role of the L.P.N. in Family Planning," By Miriam Manisoff, R.N., Reprint, Jnl. of Practical Nursing 1967 (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - "Roman Birth Control Eruption," Howard Cushman, Reprint, The Churchman 1953 (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - "[The] Roman Catholic Church," Reprint from The Nation 1947 (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - "Roman Catholics and Birth Control," Shipler, Guy Emery, Reprint, The Churchman 1941 (Box 99, Folder 18)
  - "Roots of Delinquency," undated (Box 99, Folder 19)
  - "Round the World for Birth Control," 1935 (Box 99, Folder 20)
  - "Rural Family Planning Programs," Prepared for Nat'l Adv. Commission on Rural Poverty, Edited by F. Jaffe 1967 (Box 99, Folder 21)
  - "Russia's Rublebabies," By Margaret Sanger 1944 (Box 99, Folder 22)
  - "Safe Days and Baby Days," Reprint, Reporter, Jean Lyon 1954 (Box 99, Folder 23)
  - "The Safe Period," By Dr. Carl G. Hartman 1962 (Box 99, Folder 24)
  - "Safe Period, The," Prepared by Gordon W, Perkin, M.D., Associate Medical Director 1966 (Box 99, Folder 25)
  - "[The] Safe Period," Reprint, Birth Control [Review], Matsner, Eric M., M.D. 1935 (Box 99, Folder 26)
  - Sales Helpers 1954 (Box 99, Folder 27)
  - San Francisco World Fair Exhibit, Cancellation Publicity, May 1939 (Box 99, Folder 28)
  - Sanger, Margaret, "Meddler or Martyr," 1935 (Box 99, Folder 29)
  - Sanger, Margaret, Birth Control and World Peace 1953 (Box 99, Folder 30)
  - M. Sanger, Misc. Reprint, Intro., etc. 1951, undated (Box 99, Folder 31)
  - "Save Women's Lives," undated (Box 99, Folder 32)
  - Science: Swedish Program for B.C., Reprint 1962 (Box 99, Folder 33)
  - Science: American Assn. for the Advancement of Science, Reprint 1965 (Box 99, Folder 34)
  - "Scientific Approach to Birth Control," Fairchild, Henry P., Ph.D., undated (Box 99, Folder 35)
  - "The School Counselor in Sex Education," John J. Pietrofesa, Reprint, Personal [sic, should be "Personnel"] and Guidance Journal 1976 (Box 99, Folder 36)
  - "Selective Pregnancy," Guttmacher, Alan F., M.D. 1941 (Box 99, Folder 37)
  - Senior Scholastic: "The Race Against Famine-Can It Be Won?" Reprint 1966 (Box 99, Folder 38)
  - "Ser Padre, Ser Madre," By Dr. Fritz, Spanish Version of, "To be a Father, To be a Mother," 1966 (Box 99, Folder 39)
  - Services: American Birth Control League 1935 (Box 99, Folder 40)
  - "Sex After the Baby Comes, From Real Romances," 1963, undated (Box 99, Folder 41)
  - "Sex Alphabet," undated (Box 99, Folder 42)
  - "Sex and the College Student, Some Statisical Background," Reprint, Sexual Behavior, 11/72, By the College Program, 1972 (Box 99, Folder 43)
  - Sex and Marriage, By Robert E. Hall, M.D. 1965 (Box 99, Folder 44)
  - "Sex and the Single Teenager," Leslie Aldridge Westoff 1972 (Box 99, Folder 45)
  - Sex Education 1964 (Box 99, Folder 46)
  - "Sex Education: Who Needs It?" J. D. Butts, Ed.D., Reprint, Ebony Magazine, Youth and Student Affairs 1977 (Box 99, Folder 47)
  - "Sex on the Campus and the College Health Service," A.F. Guttmacher, M.D., and Gene Vadies, Reprint by College Program, PPWP, from the Journal of the American College Health Association 1972 (Box 99, Folder 48)
  - "Sexual Energy: Constructive or Destructive?" By Dr. M.S. Calderone 1963 (Box 99, Folder 49)
  - "Sex-Related Problems: Reflections of Emotional Growth," Bruce A. Baldwin, Ph.D., Youth and Student Affairs, undated (Box 99, Folder 50)
  - "Sex vs. the Law, A Study of Hypocrisy," By Harriet F. Pilpel, Reprinted from Harper's Magazine 1965 (Box 99, Folder 51)
  - "Sexual Adjustment and Parenthood," Sanger, Margaret 1944 (Box 99, Folder 52)
  - "Sexual Functions of the Pubococcygeus Muscle," By Arnold H. Kegel, M.D. 1952 (Box 99, Folder 53)
  - Sexual Harmony in Marriage, Oliver M. Butterfield, Ph.D. 1953 (Box 99, Folder 54)
  - "Shall They Know?," 1936 (Box 99, Folder 55)
  - "Short-Term Costs and Benefits of United States Family Planning Programs," Frederick S. Jaffe, Reprint, Population Council 1974 (Box 99, Folder 56)
  - "Should the United States Start a Campaign for Fewer Births?" By Ansley J. Coale 1968 (Box 99, Folder 57)
  - Simple Contraceptive Methods, Seibels, Robert E. M.D. 1944 (Box 99, Folder 58)
  - "Sinfulness of Unplanned Parenthood," By G. Bromley Oxnam 1947 (Box 99, Folder 59)
  - "[A] Situation Almost Beyond Belief Still Exists," Out of Print 1938, 1943 (Box 99, Folder 60)
  - "Responsible Family Planning," in Social Action 1960 (Box 99, Folder 61)
  - "[The] Population Explosion," in Social Action 1958 (Box 99, Folder 62)
  - Social Action Process: Establishment of Contraceptive Services in No. Car. Health Dept., G.M. Cooper, M.D. 1946 (Box 99, Folder 63)
  - "Social and Biological Factors in Human Fertility," By Robert C. Cook 1952 (Box 99, Folder 64)
  - "Social Class and the American Social System"; "Working Class People and Family Planning," 1961 (Box 99, Folder 65)
  - "Social and Economic Data About American Cities," By Joy G. Dryfoos 1964 (Box 99, Folder 66)
  - "Social, Economic and Health Aspects of Birth Control," 1938 (Box 99, Folder 67)
  - "Social and Legal Status of Contraception," By Abraham Stone, M.D. and Harriet Pilpel 1944 (Box 99, Folder 68)
  - The Social Service Review, Reprinted with Permission by Planned Parenthood World Population 1965 (Box 99, Folder 69)
  - "Social Work and Birth Control," By Helen Glenn Tyson 1936 (Box 99, Folder 70)
  - "Society's Ounce of Prevention," By Helen Hickham Martin 1936 (Box 99, Folder 71)
  - "Soldier Takes a Wife," undated (Box 99, Folder 72)
  - "Some Neglected Aspects of Office Gynecology," Leonard H. Biskind, M.D. 1943 (Box 99, Folder 73)
  - Some Points to Remember About Legal Abortion in the U.S., Excerpts from "Legal Abortion in the U.S.: Facts and Highlights," 1974? (Box 99, Folder 74)
  - "Some Searching Questions About Planned Parenthood," 1954 (Box 99, Folder 75)
  - "Now! Something Better than...'The Pill'?" Winfield Best, McCall's 1975 (Box 99, Folder 76)
  - "Something Better than the Pill?" C.P. Gilmore, Reprint, N.Y. Times 1969 (Box 99, Folder 77)
  - "Some Unpleasant Facts about Pop. Pressures," Reprint, America 1962 (Box 99, Folder 78)
  - "Something New in Birth Control," Reprint, Reader's Digest, By Winfield Best 1965 (Box 99, Folder 79)
  - "So Please Answer," 1956, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 80)
  - "So...You Serve on a Board," undated (Box 99, Folder 81)
  - "Speaking of Planned Parenthood," (A Kit of Facts) for Speakers and Campaign Workers 1955, 1957 (Box 99, Folder 82)
  - Spermicidal Agents, Methods of Evaluating, undated (Box 99, Folder 83)
  - "Spirals, Loops and Rings Tested as Contraceptives," Med. World News, November 1963 (Box 99, Folder 84)
  - Statement on Birth Control, Quaker Women's Group 1933 (Box 99, Folder 85)
  - Statement of Birth Control, Adopted by Governing Council of American Jewish Congress 1965 (Box 99, Folder 86)
  - Statements of the Catholic Bishops of PA on State Sponsored B.C. Programs, Reprint, Evening Bulletin, Phil. 1966 (Box 99, Folder 87)
  - We Believe..."Statement of Conviction," By Nobel Laureates and Others 1961 (Box 99, Folder 88)
  - "Statement of Conviction About Overpopulation," 1960, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 89)
  - Statement by Religious Leaders, The Responsibilities of Parenthood, undated (Box 99, Folder 90)
  - "State Relief Administration and Birth Control," 1935 (Box 99, Folder 91)
  - "[The] Status of Birth Control: 1938," By Margaret Sanger, 1938 (Box 99, Folder 92)
  - Statements by President Johnson, Compiled by U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Foreign Aid, Sen. Gruening, Chrman. 1965 (Box 99, Folder 93)
  - Statement of National Importance 1939? (Box 99, Folder 94)
  - Sterility: Its Causes and Cures, By Abraham Stone. M.D., 1943 [Mislabled. Actual File: "The Margaret Sanger Research Bureau: A Twenty-year Survey," By Abraham Stone, M.D., Reprinted from Human Fertility, Sept. 1943]1943 (Box 99, Folder 95)
  - "State Responsibility in Family Planning," By George N. Shuster for University of Notre Dame 1967 (Box 99, Folder 96)
  - "Still the Most Important Thing in the World," Out of Print 1941 (Box 99, Folder 97)
  - "Stop and Go," 1966 (Box 99, Folder 98)
  - "[The] Stork is the Bird of War," By Eugene Lyons, Reprinted from Commentator 1938 (Box 99, Folder 99)
  - "[The] Story of Two Families," undated (Box 99, Folder 100)
  - "A Strategy for Implementing Family Planning Services in the United States," Jaffe, F.A., Reprint from the American Journal of Public Health 1968 (Box 99, Folder 101)
  - "Strengthening Our Nation from Within," 1940's, undated (Box 99, Folder 102)
  - "Stronger Family Life in Your [sic, should be "Our"] Community," 1947-48 (Box 99, Folder 103)
  - Structure and Function, American Birth Control League 1938 (Box 99, Folder 104)
  - Structure and Survival, By Wm. Vogt 1953 (Box 99, Folder 105)
  - Studies in Family Planning, National Family Planning Programs, Publication of Population Council 1964 (Box 99, Folder 106)
  - Studies in Human Fertility: Methods for the Control of Conception, Ortho Products 1943 (Box 99, Folder 107)
  - "[A] Study in Fertility Control," By B. Berelson and R. Freedman, Reprint from Scientific American 1964 (Box 99, Folder 108)
  - Study Outline, American Birth Control League 1935 (Box 99, Folder 109)
  - "Success in Family Planning," from True Story Magazine, Dec. 1960 (Box 99, Folder 110)
  - "Suggestion to a Philanthropist," 1937 (Box 99, Folder 111)
  - "Supporting World Wide Planned Parenthood," Projected Allocations 1964 (Box 99, Folder 112)
  - "Suppose You Were...," 1948? (Box 99, Folder 113)
  - "Syllabus," Brown, William E., M.D. 1943, 1953 (Box 99, Folder 114)
  - "Teaching on [sic, should be "of"] Contraceptive Measures in Medical Colleges," J.H.J. Upham 1943 (Box 99, Folder 115)
  - "Teaching of Contraception in Medical Schools," Abraham Stone, M.D. 1942 (Box 99, Folder 116)
  - "Teaching World Population Dynamics in Geographic Perspective," By Randall C. Anderson 1968 (Box 99, Folder 117)
  - "Technique of Contraception," 1936, 1939 (Box 99, Folder 118)
  - "Techniques of Conception Control," Dickinson and Morris 1941 (Box 99, Folder 119)
  - "Techniques of Conception Control," Reprint 1948 (Box 99, Folder 120)
  - "Techniques of Conception Control," R.L. Dickinson, 3rd Edition 1950 (Box 99, Folder 121)
  - "Technique of the Vaginal Diaphragm," Hannah M. Stone 1941 (Box 99, Folder 122)
  - "TEEN-AGERS, Marriage... Babies," Developed by PP Association of Metropolitan Washington, D.C. 1966 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - "Teen Sex: How Far Do They Really Go?" By Winfield Best, Reprint, Ladies Home Journal 1973 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Tennessee Public Welfare, "Record," By Jack Pearson, Reprint 1964 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - "Theology of Planned Parenthood," Rt. Rev. Richard S. Emrich 1953 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - "Think Money," 50th Anniversary PP 1966 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - "33,000 Doctors Speak Out on Abortion," Reprint from Modern Medicine, 1973 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - "This is Planned Parenthood World Population," Remarks by Chairman and the President, A Meeting Banquet 1963 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - "This Crowded World," By Frederick Osborn 1960 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - This is Planned Parenthood Federation, October 1957 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - "Threatening Crowd, The," By Marya Mannes, Dallas Meeting, May 1964 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - "Three Billion People," Chicago Round Table 1953 (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - "Three Essentials for Organizing Leagues and Clinics," 1937 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - "Three Hundred Million Americans Would Be Wrong," By David Lilienthal, Reprint, N.Y. Times Mag. 1966 (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - "Threshold of a New Era in Birth Control," By Dr. Alan F. Guttmacher 1957 (Box 100, Folder 14)